export const COSTINGA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Cost accounting information is used for",
A: "external exporting",
B: "internal reporting",
C: "sales promotion",
D: "statutory reporting",
answer: "B. internal reporting",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. ln evaluating performance, the Cost Accountant compares",
A: "actuals with budgets.",
B: "actuals with forecasts.",
C: "standards with budgets.",
D: "standards with forecasts",
answer: "A.  actuals with budgets.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A good Cost Accounting system must be",
A: "designed to suit the requirements of the business",
B: "objective and avoid elements of subjectivity",
C: "produced on timely basis",
D: "relevant for the intended purpose",
answer: "A.  designed to suit the requirements of the business",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Relevant Cost Accounting information is one that is",
A: "accurate and verifiable",
B: "free from bias and subjectivity.",
C: "provided on a timely basis",
D: "useful for the intended purpose",
answer: "D. useful for the intended purpose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Cost that can be influenced by the action of a given number of an organization",
A: "controllable cost",
B: "direct cost",
C: "production cost",
D: "variable cost",
answer: "A.  controllable cost",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Administration cost is the cost of",
A: "combining materials, labour and overheads to produce goods",
B: "creating and stimulating demand for the product.",
C: "formulating the-policy and directing the organization.",
D: "making the product available for dispatch to market.",
answer: "C. formulating the-policy and directing the organization.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Prime cost is the sum of all",
A: "direct cost less material cost",
B: "direct cost.",
C: "indirect cost",
D: "manufacturing cost",
answer: "B. direct cost.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Cost that cannot be traced to any particular product is",
A: "conversion cost.",
B: "direct cost.",
C: "indirect cost.",
D: "prime cost",
answer: "C. indirect cost.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Physical stocktaking takes into consideration",
A: "all goods produced during the year.",
B: "all purchases during the year",
C: "all items in the premises during the count.",
D: "all issues during the year.",
answer: "C. all items in the premises during the count.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Cost of goods issued using LIFO method of valuation is",
A: "GH¢ 27,000",
B: "GH¢ 28,200",
C: "GH¢ 28,500",
D: "GH¢ 29,400",
answer: "A.  GH¢ 27,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The value of closing the stock using the. UFO method of valuation is",
A: "GH¢ 10,800",
B: "GH¢ 11,400",
C: "GH¢ 12,000",
D: "GH¢ 16,200.",
answer: "B.  GH¢ 11,400",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The cost of stock issued using simple average is",
A: "GH¢ 28,200.",
B: "GH¢ 28,500.",
C: "GH¢ 28,714.",
D: "GH¢ 29,400",
answer: "C.  GH¢ 28,714.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. After checking the quantity of purchases delivered, the storekeeper issues a.",
A: "credit note.",
B: "goods received note",
C: "purchases order",
D: "purchases requisition",
answer: "B. goods received note",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Capital is locked up in stock when there is a",
A: "good stock management",
B: "small operating capital.",
C: "too little stock",
D: "too much stock",
answer: "D. too much stock",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The optimum amount of stock to buy in order to minimized purchasing cost is",
A: "economic order quantity",
B: "maximum stock level",
C: "re-order level",
D: "re-order quantity",
answer: "A.  economic order quantity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Idle time is the period that workers are not engaged in doing work because",
A: "of factors outside their control.",
B: "of loitering at work place.",
C: "they are on a sit down strike",
D: "they are paid low wages",
answer: "A.  of factors outside their control.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Wages for Adongo who produced 200 units is",
A: "GH¢ 1,200",
B: "GH¢ 1,500",
C: "GH¢ 2,000",
D: "GH¢ 3,800",
answer: "C.  GH¢ 2,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. How much will Bonsu earn for producing 50 units?",
A: "GH¢ 300",
B: "GH¢ 360",
C: "GH¢ 400",
D: "GH¢ 500",
answer: "A.  GH¢ 300",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. How much units will Dzifa produce to earn GH¢ 1,200?",
A: "120 units.",
B: "150 units.",
C: "170 units.",
D: "200 units",
answer: "B.  150 units.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The time rated method of labour remuneration is mostly suitable",
A: "bonus is based on extra units produced.",
B: "there is the need to increase production.",
C: "time saved is more important than units producer",
D: "units produced is not under the control of workers",
answer: "D. units produced is not under the control of workers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The process by which overheads are included in the total cost of a product is",
A: "absorption.",
B: "accumulation",
C: "allocation.",
D: "apportionments",
answer: "A.  absorption.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Over-and under absorption of overheads occur because absorbed overheads are based on",
A: "actual rates",
B: "labour hour rates",
C: "Machine hour rates",
D: "predetermined rates",
answer: "D. predetermined rates",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Overhead apportionment is the process of",
A: "allocating overheads to cost centres and cost units.",
B: "assigning overheads to cost centres and cost units.",
C: "charging overheads to cost units.",
D: "sharing overheads among cost centres.",
answer: "D. sharing overheads among cost centres.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The cost of overtime is treated in Cost Accounts as",
A: "direct labour.",
B: "distribution overheads",
C: "prime cost",
D: "production overheads",
answer: "D. production overheads",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Cost drivers are",
A: "activities that are significant determinants of cost.",
B: "areas where cost are collected based on activities that occur there.",
C: "the method of overhead absorption that suits a particular cost centre.",
D: "predetermined overhead absorption rates.",
answer: "A.  activities that are significant determinants of cost.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is a cost pool?",
A: "Machine maintenance",
B: "Maintenance hour.",
C: "Number of customers.",
D: "Number of set ups",
answer: "A.  Machine maintenance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The number of bed days available during the year is",
A: "432,000",
B: "72,000",
C: "18,000",
D: "9,000.",
answer: "A.  432,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. How many days did each patient stay on average?",
A: "45 days",
B: "25 days",
C: "8 days",
D: "1.8 days",
answer: "C.  8 days",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. What is the cost per patient per day?",
A: "Le 2,160",
B: "Le 1,200",
C: "Le 48",
D: "Le 6",
answer: "C.  Le 48",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The excess of actual losses over expected losses in process costing is",
A: "abnormal gain",
B: "abnormal loss",
C: "process loss",
D: "normal loss",
answer: "B. abnormal loss",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Scrap in processing as compared to the main product has",
A: "excess value",
B: "minimal value",
C: "no value",
D: "significant value",
answer: "B. minimal value",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Marginal costing technique is mainly used for",
A: "contract costing",
B: "decision-making.",
C: "overhead absorption",
D: "sales forecasting",
answer: "B. decision-making.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The percentage of sales that covers fixed cost and profit is measured by",
A: "breakeven point .",
B: "contribution to sales ratio.",
C: "margin to safety",
D: "overhead absorption rate",
answer: "B. contribution to sales ratio.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Selling price per unit is",
A: "D 85",
B: "D 50",
C: "D 35",
D: "D 13.50",
answer: "B. Le 100",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Breakeven point is units is",
A: "9,000 units.",
B: "3,571 units.",
C: "2,500 units.",
D: "100 units.",
answer: "B. 3,571 units.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Profit for the period is",
A: "D 575,000",
B: "D 450,000",
C: "D 325,000",
D: "D 125,000",
answer: "D. volume of production",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Breakeven analysis assumes that changes in total cost and revenue is caused by changes in",
A: "contribution per unit.",
B: "cost of production",
C: "selling price",
D: "volume of production",
answer: "C. planning and control",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The budgeting process is the main tool for",
A: "decision-making",
B: "forecasting and evaluating",
C: "planning and control",
D: "selling and distribution",
answer: "D. Variance analysis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The process by which difference between standard and actual cost is subdivided into different components is",
A: "Budgetary control.",
B: "Marginal costing",
C: "Standard costing",
D: "Variance analysis",
answer: "A.  Le 120,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Cash receipt for June is",
A: "Le 120,000",
B: "Le 114,000",
C: "Le 110,000",
D: "Le 107,500",
answer: "D. Le 107,500",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Cash payment for June is",
A: "Le 120,000",
B: "Le 114,000",
C: "Le 110,000",
D: "Le 107,500",
answer: "B. Le 114,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Total discount allowed for May and June is",
A: "Le 11,250",
B: "Le 5,750",
C: "Le 4,470",
D: "Le 2,250",
answer: "C.  Le 4,470",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Standards serve as a basis for",
A: "cost control",
B: "cost determination",
C: "Performance evaluation",
D: "Profit planning.",
answer: "C. Performance evaluation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The purpose of variance analysis is to",
A: "compute the level of variances",
B: "determine the causes of variances",
C: "set standards for the company",
D: "subdivide variances into different components",
answer: "B. determine the causes of variances",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Material price variance is the difference between",
A: "Standard price and actual price for actual quantity",
B: "standard price and actual price for standard quantity:",
C: "standard quantity and actual quantity at actual price.",
D: "standard quantity and actual quantity at standard price.",
answer: "A.  Standard price and actual price for actual quantity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. An adverse labour rate variance may be caused by",
A: "payment of unplanned overtime",
B: "poor quality materials",
C: "poor working conditions",
D: "use of lower grade labour",
answer: "D. use of lower grade labour",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The excess of overheads incurred over overheads absorbed is",
A: "adjusted overhead",
B: "over absorbed overhead.",
C: "under absorbed overhead.",
D: "variable overhead",
answer: "C. under absorbed overhead.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Production overheads incurred is recorded in",
A: "both cost and financial accounts",
B: "cost accounts only",
C: "financial accounts only",
D: "neither cost nor financial accounts",
answer: "B. cost accounts only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Cost of production is computed in the",
A: "Finished Goods Control Account.",
B: "General Ledger Control Account.",
C: "Production Overhead Control Account",
D: "Work in Progress Control Account",
answer: "D. Work in Progress Control Account",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following is non cash expenditure?",
A: "Acquisition of assets",
B: "Cash purchases.",
C: "Dividend paid.",
D: "Depreciation of assets.",
answer: "D. Depreciation of assets.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]